这真是世上最美的订婚戒指
God,that is the most beautiful engagement ring ever!
你一定很懂，你买过一大堆
You should know. You bought,like,a billion of them.
但是没有给过你
You didn't get one.
好，就是今晚了
-Tonight's the big night.
你要怎么进行？
-How you gonna ask her?
保证完美 我会带她上她最爱的餐厅
We're gonna go to her favorite restaurant.
我要送她一瓶她很喜欢的香槟 那她就知道有多贵了
I'm gonna get her favorite champagne. She'll know how expensive it is.
然后等酒倒满了，我不会敬酒
When the glasses are full,instead of proposing a toast,
我会向她求婚
I'm gonna propose.
好棒喔
It sounds perfect!
你会搞砸，让我来吧
-You'll mess it up. Let me do it.
我才不会搞砸
-I won't mess it up.
要是她说不，戒指可以给我吗
-lf she says no,can I have the ring?
她不会说不
-She won't say no.
要是
If.
没问题
-Sure.
那我呢？我也想要
-What about me? I want it too.
她不会说不
-She won't say no.
我再借给你
-I'll let you borrow it.
嗨，莫妮卡
Hey,Monica.
还给我 吞下去了
-Give it. -It's gone.
菲比
Phoebe.
嗨，莫妮卡
Hey,Monica.
我们在练习接吻喔
We're practically kissing.
本集播出：“惊喜的求婚”
The One With the Proposal
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
晚上有人有空吗？
Anyone free tonight?
我老板要主持救助儿童慈善会
My boss is hosting a charity event for kids
我带越多人去越有面子
The more people I bring,the better I look.
莫妮卡？钱德？
Monica? Chandler?
莫妮卡和钱德不能去 我们要去吃饭，记得吗？
We can't go. We're going to dinner. Remember?
天哪，真抱歉
-Oh,my God. I'm so sorry.
干嘛这么激动？
-What's the big deal?
我只是很气瑞秋不记得我们要去哪里
I get mad when Rachel doesn't remember where we're going.
你们要去哪里？
Where are you going?
那你们呢？
-How about you guys?
酒免费？ 应该是
-Open bar?-I think so.
我可以为孩子们喝酒
-I can do that for the kids.
那我也要去
I'll come.
我现在有收入 也该回馈社会了
I'm making money. It's time I give some back.
你也可以把欠我的钱还给我
You could give back the money you owe me.
好啊，你办义卖啊
Okay. Have a benefit.
罗斯 你晚上可以参加慈善晚会吗？
Ross,can you go to a charity event tonight?
不行，我跟伊丽莎白有约
I have plans with Elizabeth.
你已经在为孩童奉献爱心了
You're already doing your part for the kids.
抱歉，这是她去野营之前的最后一晚
It's our last night before she leaves for camp.
去当指导员
To be a counselor.
罗斯，我问你
I have a question.
撇开笑话不提 这段感情要往哪里走？
All jokes aside,where is this relationship going?
等等，撇开笑话不提？ 我可不同意
All jokes aside? I didn't agree to that.
你认为你们可以长久吗？ 我不知道
-Do you see this as long-term? -I don't know.
你比她大12岁喔
-You are 12 years older than her.
谁会去算？
-Who's counting?
她会，她才这么大
Well,she is. She's this many.
罗斯，她真的很年轻
Ross,she is really young.
等等，你们都这么认为吗？
Does everyone feel this way?
有一点 抱歉
-Yeah,sort of. -Sorry.
我以为你们只是爱开玩笑 我都不知道
I thought you were just making jokes. I had no idea.
不过你们都错了
You guys are wrong.
没错，我们是有年龄上的差异
Yes,there is a chronological age difference.
但是我都感觉不到 为什么？因为她很成熟
But I never notice it,because she is very mature.
况且我根本不在意你们的看法
It doesn't matter what you guys think.
跟她交往的是我，不是你们
I'm dating Elizabeth,not you.
她昨晚可不是这么说的
Not what she said last night.
他跟她就很般配
See,now,he could date her.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
嫁给我
Hey,you marry me.
怎么了，小精灵们？
-What's going on,little elves?
今晚很重要，我们想祝你好运
-It's the big night. We wish you luck.
戒指带了吗？ 就在口袋里
-You have the ring? -In my pocket.
菲比
-Phoebe. -Wha..?
麻烦你们出去 我想给她惊喜，她会看出来
Will you guys get out of here? This is a surprise.
没错，快出去
Yeah,you guys. Get out of here.
你们好
Hey,guys.
你好漂亮
-You look beautiful.
谢谢
-Thank you.
怎么了？
What's going on?
我们只是… 要参加慈善晚会觉得很兴奋
We're just really...excited about this charity event we have to go to.
给你 谢谢
-Here. -Thank you.
怎么会这样？
-So,what's going on here?
这是一场不喊价拍卖会
-Well,this is a silent auction.
要卖的东西都在这里 你写下竞标价
They lay the stuff here. You write down your offer.
出价最高的就是得主
Then the highest bid gets it.
我知道什么叫不喊价拍卖会
I know what a silent auction is.
我是说你的头发怎么会这样？
What's going on with your hair?
怎么说？
-Why?
不是啊，很好看
-No,it's nice.
瑞秋，欢迎你带了一位朋友来
Nice to see you. So glad you brought someone.
一位？我带了两位 汤普森先生，这位是菲比
Someone? I brought people. Mr. Thompson,this is Phoebe
菲比，这位是汤普森先生 他是我的部门主管
Phoebe,this is Mr. Thompson.He's the head of my department.
我还带了我的朋友乔伊…
-And I also brought my friend Joey.
虾子吐司
-Shrimp toast!
我不知道他在哪里
You know,I don't know where he is.
希望你会参加竞标
I hope you'll bid.
我正打算投标这趟巴黎之旅
Actually,I was about to bid on this lovely trip to Paris.
有眼光，祝你好运 谢谢
-Nice choice. Good luck. -Thank you.
好，20元
Okay.Twenty dollars.
把门关上，把门关上
Shut the door! Shut the door!
怎么了？
-What's going on?
对面的男生在朝我们丢水球
-Guys are throwing water balloons.
你们得报警 我都这样对付我那栋公寓的小孩
Call the cops. That's what I did to kids in my building.
这是水球仗，是我们挑起的
No,it's a water balloon fight. We started it.
听我说 我来问你晚上要不要去看演出
I stopped by to see if you wanted to see this play tonight.
这出演出应该很棒，导演…
It's excellent. The director is..
谁把神风（鸡尾酒饮料）都喝了？
-Who drank all the kamikazes?
没有，在水球里
-Nobody. We put them in here!
你要吗？ 不要
You want some?
好，我可以跟你讲一下话吗？
-Could I talk to you for a second?
当然可以
-Yeah,sure.
所以你要去看吗？ 它的剧评很好…
So this play,what do you think?It's gotten great reviews..
攻击！
-Attack!
放下水球 你们才放下
-Put your balloons down! -You put your balloons down!
统统都把水球放下
Everybody put their balloons down
这可是高级西装
Now,this is a nice suit!
请你们出去一下 我要单独跟伊丽莎白谈谈
If you'll excuse us...I would like to speak to Elizabeth alone for a moment.
丽莎，你爸好扫兴
Whoa,Liz. Your dad's a bummer.
下一项拍卖品是巴黎浪漫之旅
Our next item is the romantic trip to Paris.
由艾弥尔亚历山大 以2千3百元的高价得标
It goes to Emil Alexander with a high bid of $2300.
只差一点
So close!
你们看，我拿了几杯酒
Guys,look. Got me some drinks.
你在干什么？ 免费的酒吧嘛
-What are you doing? -Open bar.
现在酒吧都空了
Well,now it's an empty bar.
你就是见不得别人开心对吧？
You can't stand anyone else enjoying themselves,can you?
最后是今晚的最大项目
Finally,our biggest item.
22尺豪华帆船
The 22-foot Gentleman's Daysailer sailboat.
得标金额高达2万元
The winning bid was a whopping $20,000.
我赢了，我猜中了
I won.That was my guess.
什么？ 我猜2万
-What? What? What? -I guessed $20,000.
乔伊，这是拍卖会 你不是猜，是买
Joey,it is an auction. You don't guess. You buy!
什么？
What?
我没有2万
I don't have $20,000.
恭喜你购得新船… 乔伊崔比亚尼
Congratulations on your new boat,Joey Tribbiani.
坐下啦
Joey,sit down.
别理她，开心就好
Forget her. You enjoy this.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
一个国家，在神之下
"One nation...under God,
不可分割，全民拥有 自由公正（入美国籍时的誓词）
indivisible,with liberty and justice for all."
我记得是这样背，香槟来了
I remembered it. The champagne is here.
你没事吧？
-You okay?
我很好，你好吗？ 这一切…你很好吗？
-Yes. I'm good. Are you good?Is everything..? Are you perfect?
还好，其实我有点冷
Yeah. I'm okay.Actually,I'm a bit cold.
外套可以借我吗？ 可以
Can I have your jacket?
不行，我的外套不能借你
No,you can't have my jacket.
因为那样我就会冷
Because then I would be cold.
你要是觉得会冷 应该自己带外套
If you thought you'd be cold,you should've brought a jacket.
除此之外你好吗？
But,other than that,are you okay?
你真的没事吗？
-Are you sure you're okay?
对，我很好
-Yes. I'm fine.
我这段日子一直都很好 我觉得…
In fact,I've been fine for a long time now and I think...
都是拜你所赐
the reason is you.
好甜蜜喔
That's sweet.
好…
Okey
认识你之前 我的人生微不足道
Before I met you,I had really little life.
我无法想像一个人…
-And I couldn't imagine growing old..
我的天哪 我知道，不过让我说完
-Oh,my God.-I know. But let me say it.
我的天哪，理查
-Richard.
什么？我是钱德
What? I'm Chandler.
那是理查
Oh,that's Richard.
天哪，也许他没看见我们 理查
Maybe he won't see us. Richard!
莫妮卡，钱德
Monica. Chandler.
我不知道我为什么要抱你
I don't know why I did that.
见到你真好
-Good to see you.
你也是，你把头发留长了
You too. You let your hair grow.
没错，你一直希望我留长
That's right. You always wanted me to.
你又开始留胡子了
-I see your mustache is back.
我的鼻子感到寂寞
-Well,my nose got lonely.
你没留胡子，很好
You don't have a mustache,which is good.
我是钱德，我一难受就开玩笑
Chandler. I make jokes when I'm uncomfortable.
我是丽莎
-Hi,I'm Lisa. -Hi.
抱歉，丽莎
I'm sorry. Lisa,
莫妮卡，钱德 我们交往过
Monica,Chandler. We used to date
理查，我们的事应该保密
Richard,no one's supposed to know about us.
我又来了
See? I did it again.
钱德，我们坐下吧 好，我坐
-Chandler,sit down. -I'll sit down.
很高兴见到你
-Good to see you.
您的桌子准备好了
-Your table's ready,sir.
很高兴遇见你们 好
Good to see you guys.
这一桌也是空的
If you prefer,this table's available.
一起坐应该不错
That might be fun.
你在想什么？
-What were you thinking?
我不知道这是拍卖会 什么？
-I didn't know it was an auction.
我以为是猜一猜 帮助慈善团体，免费得帆船
I figured I'd take a guess. Help a charity. Free boat!
慈善团体为什么要送帆船？
Why would a charity give away a boat?
我哪知，做慈善吗？
I don't know. Charity?
你就买吧
Well,just buy the damn boat.
菲比，你喝得够多了吧？
Don't you think you've had enough to drink?
我只是在帮助儿童
I'm just helping the kids.
你喝酒怎么能帮助儿童？
How is you drinking helping the kids?
我喝得越多 孩子们喝酒就越少
Because the more I drink,the less there is for the kids to drink.
崔比亚尼先生
Mr. Tribbiani,
你的慷慨解囊 让兴建活动中心的事大有进展
your contribution brings us...a step closer to building the youth center.
我很高兴你带他来 我也是
-I'm so happy you brought him. -So am I.
我很好奇，那艘船值多少？
I'm curious. How much is that boat worth?
差不多是1万9
-I think it was valued at 19,000.
我猜得蛮准的
-Hey,I was pretty close.
坏消息 我不能买那艘船，我没有钱
So,bad news.I can't buy the boat. I don't have any money.
乔伊，你真幽默
Joey! Joey,good one. He's silly.
你真会演
Good! Very good!
好吧，我要逃了
-So I think I'm gonna take off now.
你不能走，乔伊
-You can't leave,Joey!
你答应要买船，具有约束力
You agreed to buy that boat. It's a contract.
而且你走了 我的主管会宰了我
Plus,if you leave,my boss will kill me.
那怎么办？我没有那么多钱
I don't have that kind of money.
我知道，好…
I know. Okay,okay.
好，这样吧 我们去找出价第二高的人
This is what we'll do.We'll let the next highest bidder buy it.
然后让他们去买 你只要付差价
Then you'll pay the difference.
好
Okay.
这些小孩要活动中心干嘛
I don't know why the kids need a youth center anyway.
放了学跟我一样看电视就好了
They should just watch TV after school like I did.
我现在也蛮好的
I turned out fine.
但是不优秀
Not great.
我帮助儿童帮到想吐
I'm helping the kids so much I think I'm gonna throw up.
我们躲在洗手间里
So we're hiding in the bathroom...
然后我溜出来
I get out.
但莫妮卡还没出来 她父母就进去了
But before she can,her parents come in.
于是我躲到浴帘后面 接着他们就在地上做起来了
I hide in the shower. They start going at it on the floor.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
我有一个，我有一个
I got a good one.
我有一次撞见我父母 跟同一个男人做爱
I once walked in on both my parents making love to the same guy.
遇见你们真的好开心 我想敬酒
It's so great seeing you guys again. I'd like to make a toast.
正如一位诗人所说 “在友谊的甜蜜里”
As a poet once said,"In the sweetness of friendship...
“尽情欢笑，分享欢乐吧”
Let there be laughter and sharing of pleasures.
“人心正是从中获得朝气” “焕然一新”
In the dew of little things,the heart finds its morning and is refreshed."
什么？
What?
天哪，你们
Oh,my God! You guys!
在你开口之前，我们有事要说
Have we got a story for you.
你猜我们吃饭时遇见谁？ 谁？
Guess who we bumped into?-Who?
理查 什么？
-Richard! -What？
没错，那个餐厅也是理查最爱的
Right,that's Richard's favorite place too.
所以你早知道？很好
-Oh,you knew that? Good.
你不是要跟伊丽莎白约会吗？
-Weren't you going out with Elizabeth?
没错，但是她忙着打水球仗
I was. She was a little busy with a water balloon fight.
有时大人就是不会兑现他们的承诺
Sometimes grownups have commitments they can't get out of.
也许她真的太年轻了
Maybe she is too young for me.
当我看到她跟朋友横冲直撞 我觉得我好像保姆
When I was over there,I felt like I was a babysitter.
我终于开始了解你们的话
I see what you were talking about.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
你可以比较这段感情的利弊
Weigh the good stuff about her against the bad.
我当初就是这样…
That's what I did when I first started...
比较东西的
weighing stuff.
好，弊
Okay,bad stuff.
我比她大12岁
I'm 12 years older than she is.
学校发现会开除你
The school could fire you.
她要离开3个月 去参加野营
-She's leaving for three months. -For camp.
好，利
Okay,good stuff.
她很甜很漂亮…
Well,she's sweet and pretty and..
性爱方面很赞吧？
And the sex is probably great,huh?
如果你是指很温柔又互相尊重
It's tender and respectful,if that's what you mean.
罗斯，你只需要问你自己 你看得见未来吗？
The only thing you need to ask is,"Do you see a future?"
你能想像跟她结婚吗？
Do you see yourself marrying her?
天哪，你已经娶她了对不对？
My God. You married her,didn't you?
没有啦，我只是…
No,I didn't do that. It's just...
好吧，我觉得我们没什么未来
Okay,honestly,no. I don't see a big future with her.
那这就是你的答案了
Okay,I think that's your answer.
我得告诉她 我最恨这个步骤了
I gotta talk to her. I hate this part.
你必须忘记伊丽莎白
Forget Elizabeth.
你要是不小心 今年可能会结不到婚
If you're not careful...you may not get married at all this year.
你今晚不是要做某件事吗？
-Weren't you supposed to do something?
祝你俩分手顺利，伙计
-Good luck with Elizabeth,my man.
天哪，菲比，你喝了几杯？
My God,Phoebe,how many have you had?
一，二，三… 七乘以三，二十一杯
1,2,3... Seven times three.. 21!
你一定醉翻了
-You must be just wasted!
是有点累
-I'm a little tired.
瑞秋
Rach
出价第二高的人在一号桌 太好了
-Next highest bidder is at table one. -Great.
标到巴黎之旅的人坐四号桌 好
The guy with the Paris trip is at table four.
你干嘛管谁赢得巴黎之旅？
-Why do you care about who won?
那是双人之旅，失陪
-It's a trip for two.Excuse me.
抱歉，标到巴黎之旅的人 在这一桌吗？
Is the person who won the Paris trip at this table?
我就是
-That was me.
真迷人
-Enchante.
抱歉，有没有一位波芒先生？ 我就是
-Is there a Mr. Bowmont at this table? -That's me.
你好 你今天走运了，波芒先生
Well,hello. This is your lucky day,Mr. Bowmont.
那艘帆船又要卖了
The Gentleman Daysailer has become available again...
你开了1万8的价格
and I believe you made a bid of $18,000.
你得付钱，不是猜猜而已的
You have to pay that. It's not just a guess.
我没标到船还松了一口气 我老婆会宰了我
I was relieved I didn't win. My wife would've killed me.
不会吧？她会爱死这艘船
You kidding? She'll love this boat!
是啊，尊夫人芳名？
-What is your wife's name?
她叫潘
-Pam
潘，天哪，想像一下
Just imagine this:
“潘号”
The Pam
我想她不会喜欢
I don't think she'd like that.
那想像…“波芒先生号”
Okay. Imagine this: The Mr. Bowmont.
还是不要了
-I don't think so.
让我为你描绘一下
-Let me paint you a little picture
你在哈德逊河上航行（贯穿纽约的一条河）
You are setting sail up the Hudson.
风吹过你的…手臂
You've got the wind in your... arms.
你得到你企盼已久的安宁
You get all that peace and quiet you've always wanted.
你回到大自然怀抱 你可以钓鱼
You get back to nature. You can go fishing.
你可以买一顶帽子 让大家叫你船长
You get one of those hats. People call you captain.
等你老了就是老船长
And then when you're old,Cappy.
管他的，不买说不过去 我买了
-It's for a good cause. All right.
你别想，船是我的
-No way! It's mine!
什么？
What?
你刚才说的那些事我也要
The stuff you said,I want that!
但是乔伊，你没有2万
-But you don't have $20,000!
管他的，我分期，怎样都好 我要“波芒先生号”
Who cares? I'll make payments! I want the Mr. Bowmont!
天哪，你们回来了
-Oh,my God. You're back.
让我看你的手，让我看你的手
-Let me see it. Let me see your hand.
你为什么要看我的手？
Why do you wanna see my hand?
我想看你手上拿的垃圾
I wanna see what's in your hand. I wanna see the trash.
好脏，你最好拿去扔
It's all dirty. You should throw this out.
好
Okey
你们搞什么？
-What did you just do?
怎么回事？
-What happened?
理查也在，我无法开口
-Richard was there. I couldn't do it.
不会吧
-Oh,no.
我要延到明天，给她惊喜 却被你们破坏了
I was gonna surprise her tomorrow.Now you've ruined it.
我们没有破坏
We didn't.
谁会一进门就要看别人的手？
Who walks in a room and asks to see a person's hands?
算命师、修指甲的小姐 手部医生…
A palm reader,a manicurist,a hand doctor...
手套推销员 漂亮
-Glove salesman. -Good one!
真惨，我该怎么办？
This is terrible. What will I do?
她只是在怀疑，又不是确定 你可以唬她
She only suspects something. So just throw her off the track.
也对，我可以让她觉得 我完全不考虑结婚
I'll pretend marriage is the last thing on my mind.
没错，让她相信你很害怕承诺
Convince her you're scared of commitment,
让她相信你有点孬种
that you're a coward.
我做得到，我练了30年
I can do that. I've had years of practice.
你这个人总算有价值了
Being you is finally gonna pay off!
我不得不跑去地下室扔
I had to go all the way to the basement because
某个白痴小孩老是用披萨盒 把垃圾槽堵住
Some idiot keeps stuffing the trash chute with pizza boxes.
那个家伙还是没改？
That guy is still doing that?
天哪，你们回来了 我看看你的手
Oh,my God. Let me see your hand!
来不及了 她已经把垃圾拿去扔了
You're too late! She already took out the trash!
伊丽莎白，我们得谈一谈
Look,Elizabeth,we have to talk.
我跟别人分手没这么平和过
I have never had such a healthy breakup.
她表现得好成熟
She was such a grownup about it.
我觉得她一点也不幼稚
She didn't seem too immature for me.
我是不是犯了个大错？
Did I just make a huge mistake?
罗斯，等等
Ross! Wait!
伊丽莎白，太好了 我正在想说…
Elizabeth,thank God. I was just thinking about..
你最烂了
You suck!
什么？
What?
好，我们仍在分手中
Breakup's still on
她来了 我像不像不想结婚的人？
Here she comes. Do I look like I don't wanna get married?
像，还有点像法国人
And,also,a little like a French guy.
我第一次发现
I never noticed that before.
你们在干什么？
-What are you up to?
消磨时间，聊网站
-Hanging out. Talking about websites.
有一个网站在讨论婚姻 及婚姻的一无是处
We saw this interesting website about marriage...and how unnecessary it is,
说那只是政府监视你的方式
a way for the government to keep tabs.
是啊，专制
Yeah,Big Brother.
有点夸张，不过很高兴你们总算上了 其他类别的网站
That's a bit crazy.Although I am glad you're looking at other things on the lnternet.
不过我就想 为什么会有人想要结婚？
Got me thinking. Why would anybody want to get married?
为什么？因为要赞颂这段感情 要巩固你们的承诺
To celebrate the relationship,solidify the commitment...
要向全世界宣布你们的爱
declare your love for one another to the world.
能知道你的反应真好
Well,that's good to know.
“波芒先生号”来了
The Mr. Bowmont is here!
莫妮卡 有一位客人想向主厨致意
A diner wants to compliment you.
要让他进来吗？
Shall I let him in?
当然，我最爱这种事了
Sure. I love this part.
进来吧
-Come on in. -Hi.
理查
-Richard.
其实我不是来向主厨致意的
-I'm not here to compliment the chef.
没关系 我最讨厌客人跑来致意
I hate when people come back to compliment the chef.
好像我很闲似的
Like I have nothing better to do.
你有什么事？
So,what's up?
那天晚上遇见你很开心
It was great seeing you the other night.
我也很开心
Good to see you too.
你就是来说这个的？
-You came to tell me that?
不是，我是来说别的
-I came to tell you something else.
我是来说我仍然爱你
I came here to tell you I still love you.
什么？你刚才…什么？
What? What did you..? What?
我仍然爱你
I still love you.
我知道我甚至不该告诉你
I know I shouldn't even be here telling you this.
你跟钱德在一起，我很喜欢他
You're with Chandler,who I like.
你说他是异性恋，我就相信你
If you say he's straight,I'll believe you.
但见到你之后 我知道我不说会后悔一辈子
After seeing you,I knew if I didn't tell you I'd regret it.
放弃你是我所做过最蠢的事
Letting you go was the stupidest thing I ever did.
你不该到厨房来的
You're really not supposed to be back here.
我知道，对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道时机地点都不对 但是…
I know this is the wrong time and the wrong place...
我一定要说
but I had to tell you.
我想跟你共度一生，我想娶你
I wanna spend my life with you. I wanna marry you.
我想跟你生儿育女
I wanna have kids with you.
上帝啊，这里为什么没摆椅子？
Oh,my God. Why don't they put chairs back here?
我知道我这很疯狂 已经来不及了吗？
Look,I know this is crazy,but am I too late?
没错 你3年前怎么不说这些话？
You're too late. Where was all this three years ago?
我知道，我是个白痴
I know. I was an idiot.
我也想忘记你，真的
I tried to forget you. I really did.
我们去年吃完饭
After our last lunch,
我跑去非洲6个月想忘记你
I spent six months in Africa trying to forget.
你去非洲做什么？ 帮助盲童
-What did you do there? -Work with blind kids.
你折磨我嘛
What are you doing to me?
很抱歉，我们之间是不可能的
I'm sorry,but this is not gonna happen.
好，我会离开 再也不会来烦你
That's fine. I'll walk away. I'll never bother you again.
但前提是 钱德也愿意给你这一切
Only if you say Chandler's willing to give you everything I am.
他愿意
Well,he is. I mean...
没错，他成天把婚姻挂在嘴边
marriage is all he talks about. My goodness!
事实上是我在让他等
In fact,I'm the one making him wait.
是吗？ 对
You are? Why?
为什么？
Why?
因为政府的阴谋
Because of the government.
很棒吧？ 莫妮卡和钱德要结婚了
Isn't it incredible?Monica and Chandler are getting married.
就是啊，他们会很幸福
I know. They'll be so happy together.
两个最要好的朋友坠入爱河 这种机率有多大？
How often do two best friends fall in love?
并不太大 没错
-Not that often. -No.
我好替他们开心
-I'm so happy for them.
我也是，好开心
-Me too. So happy for them.
我很高兴，毫无嫉妒之心
I'm so happy and not at all jealous.
没错，当然没有
Oh,no! God,definitely not jealous.
我可能是98%开心2%嫉妒
I'm probably 98% happy and maybe 2% jealous.
2%等于没有 没错
-I mean,what's 2%? That's nothing. -Totally.
我是九比一 我也是
-I'm like 90/10. -Yeah. Me too.
你们有见到钱德吗？
Have you guys seen Chandler?
没有，但你知道谁来找过你？
No. But you know who was looking for you?
坦妮尔 （《船长与坦妮尔》的女主角）
Tennille.
你昨天说的那些话
The marriage stuff you were saying yesterday?
应该不是真心话吧？ 当然是
You don't believe that.Sure,I do.
事实上我觉得婚姻本身 就很不近人情
In fact,I think the concept of marriage is unnatural.
你看猪嘛，我们来看一下猪
Look at pigs. Let's take a second here and look at pigs.
猪不会有固定配偶
Pigs don't mate for life.
猪的一生可以有一百个性伴侣
A pig can have 100 sexual partners in a lifetime.
那还只是普通的猪 而不是擅长运动的猪
That's an ordinary pig,not even a pig that's good at sports.
对，但那是猪不是人
Yeah,but that's pigs,not people.
如果结婚行得通我绝对支持 但是你知道美国的离婚率吗？97%
If marriage worked,I'd be for it. Do you know the divorce rate?Ninety-seven percent!
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是说你可能永远都不想结婚
Are you telling me you may never want to get married?
谁说的？ 你啊，你说的
-Who's to say? -You! You are to say!
话不能说死，不过应该是…
Never say never,but,probably...
永远不会
yeah,never.
天哪，那我们在干什么？ 现在是怎样？
Oh,my God. Then what are we even doing? What is this?
干嘛对我施压？
Whoa,whoa,whoa! What is all this pressure?
这是某种新策略吗？
Is this some new strategy?
你别再搞尔虞我诈那一套了
Why don't you put down your copy of The Rules,huh,mantrap?
你知道吗？我要走了
You know what? I gotta go.
放心，我自有打算
It's okay. I got a plan.
我们会找到真爱的 一定会的
-We're gonna find love. -Definitely.
我对这点有信心
Yeah,I'm pretty confident about that.
所以我可以有八成 替莫妮卡和钱德高兴
That's what makes it so easy to be 80% happy for Monica and Chandler.
不过要是有保障就好了
-A guarantee would be nice.
什么意思？
-What do you mean?
有些人不是会跟朋友约定
Some friends make a deal.
要是两个人到了40都没结婚 他们就要结婚
Like if neither of them are married by 40,they marry each other.
你是指候补？ 没错
-A backup? -Exactly.
我已经找好了
Yeah,I've got that.
你找好了？
You do?
是谁？ 乔伊
-Who? -Joey.
乔伊？ 对
-Joey?
真的还假的？ 我好几年前就锁定他了
Are you serious? -I locked him in years ago.
所以要是你们40岁还没结婚
Wait. So if neither of you are married by 40,
你就要嫁给乔伊
you'll marry Joey?
对，我们握手为定
Yep. We shook on it.
不过相信我 他可不想只此而已
But believe me,that is not how he wanted to seal the deal.
是吗？
Oh,seriously?
对，他说的是…
I think his exact words were..
真迷人
Charming.
只是个候补
He's just a backup.
莫妮卡
-Hey,Monica.
你有见到瑞秋吗？或是镜子？
-Have you seen Rachel? Or a mirror?
这是我的船长装，酷吧？
-It's for my boat. Pretty cool,huh?
很酷
-Yeah,it's great.
怎么了？告诉船长
What's wrong? Talk to the captain.
我又发现这段感情是死路一条
Just realizing I'm in a dead-end relationship.
钱德欺负你是吧？
-Chandler being difficult?
我又不是明天就要结婚
-I don't want marriage tomorrow.
我只是想知道 我不是在原地打转，浪费时间
But I wanna know we're going somewhere,that I'm not wasting time.
你也了解钱德
-You know Chandler.
我已经不了解钱德了
-No,I don't know Chandler.Not anymore.
仿佛有什么事变了
It's like something's changed.
也许是你变了？
-Maybe you changed.
我才没变
-I didn't change.
也许问题就在这里
Maybe that's the problem.
什么？
-What?
钱德很复杂，不太可能娶妻
-Chandler is a complex fellow.One who is unlikely to take a wife.
这是跑船人的用语吗？
Is that some kind of boat talk?
我还没想好在船上的说话风格
I haven't totally decided how to talk on my boat yet.
他以为我会空等下去吗？
Does he think I'll wait around for nothing?
面对现实吧，钱德反对婚姻 他是不会变了
Face it. Chandler is against marriage.And always will be
有些人可是真心想娶我
There's some people who do wanna marry me.
有吗？
-There are?
有，理查
-Yeah. Richard.
理查说他想娶你？
Richard said he wants to marry you?
钱德说他痛恨婚姻？ 没错
-And Chandler says he hates marriage? -That's right.
钱德热爱婚姻
Chandler loves marriage!
你刚才说他痛恨婚姻
You just said he hates marriage!
说他很复杂，不太可能娶妻
"He's a complex fellow who's unlikely to take a wife"!
说他会永远反对婚姻
"He's against marriage and always will be"!
你对我刚才说的话是这样理解的？
You got that from what I said?
白垩纪结束，恐龙也从此绝迹
After the Cretaceous Period,the dinosaurs were gone.
你们发生了什么事？
What happened,you guys?
瑞秋 嘿你
-Rach. -Hey,you.
请进 谢谢
-Come on in. -Thank you.
很遗憾你跟伊丽莎白分手了
I'm so sorry to hear about you and Elizabeth.
谢谢，我以为我们能克服万难 不过…
Thanks. I really thought we'd be able to make it work.
这大概是命中注定的
I guess it wasn't meant to be.
是啊，爱情…爱情真是微妙，对吧
Yeah. Love. It's a tricky business,isn't it?
是啊
-I guess so.
我们要不要来做个约定
So,what do you say we make a pact?
要是我们到了40都还没结婚 我们就结婚
If you and I are both single by 40,we get married.
我们互相认识，互相喜欢
I mean,we know each other,we like each other...
我们已经上过床，不会有意外
we've already slept together,so there'll be no surprises.
不会觉得“搞什么？”
No,like,"What's that?"
你想找我当候补？ 没错
-Oh,you want me to be your backup. -Exactly.
我已经有候补了
Yeah. I already have one.
是谁？ 菲比
-What? Who? -Phoebe.
菲比？
Phoebe?
但是她说乔伊是她的候补
But she just said Joey is her backup.
才不是呢
Oh,I don't think so.
罗斯，我刚跟她聊过 她说她和乔伊约好了
We just spoke. She said that she and Joey made a deal.
不可能的，我们早就约好了 还握手为定
That's impossible. We have had a deal for years. We shook on it.
只不过她觉得握手还不够…
Although,believe me,she wanted to do a lot more than that.
甘瑟，我是乔伊，钱德在吗？
Gunther,it's Joey. Is Chandler there?
我问你，在海上航行时都吃哪一种松糕
Listen. What kind of muffins do they serve at sea?
你上哪去了？
Where the hell have you been?!
我在跟教授做椰子电话
I was making a coconut phone with the Professor.
理查跟莫妮卡说他想娶她
Richard told Monica he wants to marry her.
什么？
-What?
就是啊，我一直想去找你 叫你别玩了
-I've been trying to find you.
可是这双死海员鞋子跑一跑就掉
And I would have if these damn boat shoes wouldn't keep flying off!
我的天哪 就是啊，烂死了
-Oh,my God! -I know! They suck!
他不该向我的女朋友求婚 该求婚的人是我
He's not supposed to ask her to marry him! I am!
我知道 那…
-I know! -What..?
你知道吗？我要去找他教训他
You know what I'll do? I'll go over there and kick his ass!
你愿意帮忙吗？
Will you help me?
钱德，被他海扁一顿不是办法
Look,I don't think us getting our asses kicked is a solution,okay?
赶快去找莫妮卡吧
-Look,just go and find Monica.
你说得对，好
-You're right.Okay.
我去拿戒指，我去拿戒指
I'm gonna get the ring...
我要找到她，直接向她求婚
I'm gonna go find her and I'm gonna propose!
老兄 怎样？
Dude! Dude! Dude!
你的椰子电话 也许很适合摆在船上
That coconut phone might be good for the boat.
我不知道我来干什么
I don't know why I'm here.
我又没问
I didn't ask.
你要进来吗？ 我不知道
-You wanna come in? -I don't know.
好吧
Oh,okay.
那我把门开着，回去坐下
I'll just leave the door open and sit on the couch.
钱德真是个白痴
-Chandler is such an idiot!
喝酒吧？
-Drink?
好，我要威士忌加… 冰块和莱姆片？我记得
-Scotch on the.. -Rocks with a twist?I remember.
还在抽雪茄？
You still smoking cigars?
没有，那是艺术
No,no. That's art.
如果你不喜欢 我可以把艺术熄掉
If it bothers you,I can put my art out.
没关系
No,that's okay.
莫妮卡，我问你一件事
So,Monica,let me ask you a question.
我们分手后，你想过我吗？
Since we broke up,do you ever...think about me?
我2个月前还想到你
Actually,I thought about you a few months ago.
是吗？
-Really?
不过是因为我去做眼睛检查 又不喜欢我的新医生
-But it's because...I had an eye exam,and I don't like my new eye doctor.
是谁？ 爱德华奈夫斯基
-Who is it? -Edward Nevsky.
他的确很差
He's no good.
你有想过非眼科医生的我吗？
Do you ever think about me...-in a non-eye-doctor way?
没有
No.
但忘记你是我这辈子最难的事
Because getting over you was the hardest thing I've ever done.
我不让自己想到你
I never let myself think about you.
菲比
Phoebe,
你找了乔伊和罗斯？ 你不能有两个候选
you picked Joey and Ross?You can't have two backups!
当然可以 眼光独到才会替候选找候选
Of course I can.It's good sense to back up your backup.
我已经失去钱德了 什么？
-Look,I've already lost Chandler. -What?
菲比，我们都是你的候选？
Hey,Phoebe! We're both your backup?
菲比，你怎么可以这样？
How could you do this to me?
我不知道你们在抱怨什么 你们都知道这个状况
Why are you complaining? You were both aware of the situation.
我们不知道 我不知道
-I was not! -No,we weren't!
婚后你们可不能这样顶嘴
This kind of backtalk won't fly when we're married.
菲比，你不能独占他们 你得选一个
You can't have both. Pick one.
选我 不，选我，我不想当老处女
-Pick me! -No,pick me!I don't wanna end up an old maid.
好吧，我看看
All right. Well,let's see.
罗斯是个好爸爸
Ross is a good father.
但是乔伊有船，好难选喔
But...Joey has a boat. This is hard.
太不可思议了，我要换成瑞秋
This is crazy. I wanna switch to Rachel.
我也要换成瑞秋
-I wanna switch to Rachel too.
不，等一下
-No,wait. Just wait.
你们别急着做决定
Wait,guys. Don't make any rash decisions.
记得我的承诺吧？结婚之后 1星期三次
Just remember my promise:If we get married,three times a week.
天哪，菲比 我是说按摩
Oh,my God. Phoebe...I'm talking about massages.
当然不是啦
No,I'm not.
我知道该怎么解决了 办法就是
I know how to settle it. We'll do this.
我在一张纸巾上写乔伊 一张纸巾上写罗斯
I'm gonna write "Joey" on one napkin...and "Ross" on the other napkin
然后我们一人选一张 那个人就是我们的候选
and we're gonna pick one.That person will be our backup.
好吗？
Okay?
很公平
-Sounds fair.
那好，我来弄乱
-All right.Good. Switching them up.
选一边 左边
-Pick one. -Left.
谢谢 不客气
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
罗斯 乔伊
-Ross. -Joey.
我们交换吧 没错
-We should switch. -Absolutely.
我想念你 丑不啦叽的扁脸老怪物
I missed you,you ugly flat-faced old freak.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
他啦
Him.
我想念这间房子 这才是大人的房子
I missed this apartment. Now,this is a grownup's apartment.
我应该跟大人在一起，你懂吧
I should be with a grownup,you know?
是的，你是说你要跟比较成熟的人在一起
You're saying you need to be with someone more mature.
也许是一个…有医师执照的人
Maybe someone with...a license to practice medicine.
或是有胡子的人
Or a mustache.
说真的，我不是小孩子了
Let's face it. I'm not a kid anymore.
我需要一个目标相同的人
I need someone who wants the same things.
来我工作的地方跟我示爱 我要的是那样
Coming to my work and telling me you love me,I want that!
吃饭时聊猪的性爱 我不要那样
Talking about pig sex over lunch,I don't want that!
很公平
I think that's fair.
公平？别跟我提公平
Please,don't even talk to me about fair.
公平的意思是你当年想娶我
Fair would've been you wanting to marry me then.
或是钱德现在想娶我
Or Chandler wanting to marry me now.
这整件事一点也不公平
Believe me,nothing about this is fair. Nothing.
不公平不公平不公平… 别激动
-Nothing! Nothing! -It's okay.
不公平
Nothing.
我不…我不知道
I don't know.I don't know.
我知道
I know.
我得先把事情想清楚
I have to figure some..Some stuff,
然后才能… 我懂
before I can...I understand.
你只管慢慢想
Take as much time as you want.
10分钟、20分钟都行
Ten,even 20 minutes,if you need it.
我会在这里，不会抽烟
I'll be here. Not smoking.
钱德
Chandler
她人呢？我可不怕你
Where is she?I'm not scared of you.
她不在，请进
She's not here. And please come in.
威士忌加冰和莱姆片 放在杯垫上？
Scotch on the rocks...with a twist,on a coaster.
莫妮卡，莫妮卡
Monica?
好吧，她来过，又走了
Okay,she was here. But she left.
她去哪里？
Where did she go?
她说她要想清楚
She said she had to think things over.
天哪，我真不敢相信 我以为…
Oh,my God. I can't believe this. I thought
我以为你是个好人
you were a good guy.
我们又没怎样？
Look,nothing happened.
没怎样？没怎样？
Nothing?
你没跟我女朋友示爱？
So you didn't tell my girlfriend you love her?
好吧，只有这样
Well,all right,one thing happened.
我真不敢相信 你知道你做了什么？
You know what you did?
我的女朋友在想事情
My girlfriend is thinking things over.
你让我的女朋友思考
You made my girlfriend think!
我很抱歉
Well,I'm sorry.
她还需要想什么？我爱她
-What's to think about? I love her. -Well...
我愿意给她你不愿意给的东西
I'm willing to offer her things that you aren't.
但是我愿意给 我只是故意要让她失望
I'm willing to offer her those things. I had a plan...to throw her off
等真相大白，她就会很惊喜
so when I offered all these things,she'd be surprised.
那效果真的很好
If it helps,it worked very well.
你的出现破坏了计划，你这颗大树
It was working till you showed up,you big tree.
这样不公平
This isn't fair.
你曾经有机会，结果你搞砸了
You had your chance with her,and you blew it!
现在轮到我了，我不会搞砸 因为我们是天生一对
This is my chance. I won't blow it,because we are meant for each other.
而这一切只是个愚蠢的错误
And this has all just been one stupid mistake!
我本来打算今晚求婚的
I was gonna propose tonight.
你要求婚？
-You were gonna propose?
对，我还…
-Yeah,I even...
准备了戒指，你有吗？
got a ring. Did you get a ring?
没有，我没准备
No,I don't have a ring.
你去找她吧，钱德
You go get her,Chandler.
我可以给你一个忠告吗？ 要是你得到了她
And can I give you a piece of advice?If you do get her...
一定要好好把握，相信我
don't let her go.Trust me.
理查…你的确是个好人
You know,Richard,you are a good guy.
我知道
I know.
真讨厌
I hate that.
钱德
Chandler
待会再说，我得去找莫妮卡 她走了
-I've gotta find Monica. -She's gone.
什么？
-What?
她走了，提着一个包走了
-She had a bag and she left.
你在说什么？
-What?
她哭得很伤心 说你们要的东西不一样
-She was all crying...She said you guys want different things.
说她需要时间思考
and that she needed time to think
你为什么不拦住她？ 不说出我的打算？
-Why didn't you tell her it was a plan?
我有啊，我都说了 但是她不信
I told her everything.But she wouldn't believe me.
那她…她上哪去了？
Well,where..? Where did she go?
她父母家，她叫你不要打电话给她
To her parents'. She said you shouldn't call. B
要是我就会打
ut if I were you,I would.
我居然搞砸了
-I can't believe I ruined this.
我很遗撼
-I am so sorry,man.
你希望是个惊喜的
You wanted it to be a surprise.
天哪
Oh,my God.
钱德…我这辈子…
Chandler...in all my life...
从来没想过我会这么幸运
I never thought I would be so lucky...
可以…爱上我最要好的…
as to fall in love with my best...
我最要好的…
My best...
这就是为什么女人从不求婚的原因 好好好
There's a reason why girls don't do this!
我来，我以为…
I'll do it. I thought...
等等，我一定行
Wait,I can do this.
我以为开口的时间地点很重要
I thought that it mattered...what I said or where I said it.
后来才发现唯一重要的是你…
Then I realized...the only thing that matters is that you...
让我得到超乎想像的幸福
You make me happier than I ever thought I could be.
所以如果你愿意
And if you let me...
我愿意用下半生 让你跟我一样幸福
I'll spend all my life trying to make you feel the same way.
莫妮卡…
Monica...
你愿意嫁给我吗？
will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes.
我就知道你应该会娶妻
I knew you were likely to take a wife!
可以进去了吗？我们快憋死了
Can we come in yet? We're dying out here!
进来，进来
Come in! Come in!
我们订婚了
We're engaged!
这是我最不嫉妒的时候
This is the least jealous I've ever been.
等等，不行啦，罗斯不在
Oh,no,wait! This is wrong! Ross isn't here!
他都做过三次这样的事了 知道是怎么回事
Hell,he's done it three times. He knows what it's about!
亲爱的，你今晚如此美丽
Oh my darling，you are wonderful tonight